Hyung-Kwon Ko

College of Computing KAIST, Daejeon hyungkwonko@gmail.com https://hyungkwonko.info

About

Hyung-Kwon Ko is a researcher at KAIST Interaction Lab. His main research areas include Human-Computer Interaction, Human-Centered AI, and Information Visualization. He designs, prototypes, and evaluates interactive systems to innovate people's working paradigms based on a thorough investigation of their need. Experienced in AI models from both academia and industry, he is currently interested in how foundation models (e.g., DALL-E) could help people in visual art domains perform creative works.

Education

| 2019 – 2021 | Seoul National University , Seoul, Korea Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (Advisor: Dr. Jinwook Seo) |
|-------------|---|
| 2014 – 2019 | Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, Minor in Industrial Engineering |

Publications

CONFERENCE & JOURNAL PAPERS

- [a5] Ko, H.-K.*, An, S.*, Park, G., Kim, S.K., Kim, D., Kim, B., Seo, J. (2022).
 We-toon: A Communication Support System between Writers and Artists in Collaborative Webtoon Sketch Revision.
 Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST '22), 14 pages.
- [a4] Jeon, H.*, Ko, H.-K.*, Lee, S., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2022).

 Uniform Manifold Approximation with Two-phase Optimization.

 Proceedings of IEEE Conference on Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS '22), 5 pages.
- [a3] Jeon, H., Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2021).

 Measuring and Explaining the Inter-Cluster Reliability of Multidimensional Projections.

 IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (In Proceedings of VIS '21), 28(1):551-561.
- [a2] Jung, S., Choe, K., Park, S., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2021).
 Mixed-Initiative Approach to Extract Data from Pictures of Medical Invoice.
 IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis '21), 111-115.
- [a1] Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2020).

 Progressive Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection.

 EG/VGTC Conference on Visualization (EuroVis '20), 133-137.

Preprints & Publications in Progress

- [b6] Ko, H.-K., Son, K., Jin, H., Choi, Y., Kim, J. (2022).

 Crowdiffusion: Text Prompting of Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models by Example.

 (In Progress)
- [b5] Shin, H., Lee, Y., Ko, H.-K., Kim, J. (2022).

 Enabling Prototyping of Al-infused UIs with Task-level Specifications.

 (In Progress)
- Yun, S., Jeon, H., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2022).
 Scalable Readability Evaluation of Graph Layouts on Distributed Environments. (In Progress)

[b3] Ko, H.-K., Park, G., Jeon, H., Jo, J., Kim, J., Seo, J. (2022).

Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models for Visual Artists' Creative Works.

Arxiv Preprint (Under Review)

[b2] Choi, J.*, Song, J.*, Jeon, H., Kim, Y., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2022).

How Disentanglement Affects Users' Interpretation, Control, and Sentiment when Using Generative

Models. (Under Review)

[b1] Jeon, H., Aupetit, M., Lee, S., Ko, H.-K., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2022).

Distortion-Aware Brushing for Interactive Cluster Analysis in Multidimensional Projections.

Arxiv Preprint (Under Review)

Experience

| 06/2022 – Present | KAIST Interaction Lab | (KIXLAB), Daejeon, Korea |
|-------------------|-----------------------|--------------------------|
|-------------------|-----------------------|--------------------------|

Researcher (Advisor: Dr. Juho Kim)

10/2021 – 06/2022 Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea

AI Research Scientist, Webtoon AI

04/2021 – 10/2021 Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea

AI Research Intern, Webtoon AI, (Mentor: Dr. Daesik Kim)

03/2019 – 08/2019 Human-Computer Interaction Lab, Seoul, Korea

Research Intern (Advisor: Dr. Jinwook Seo)

01/2019 – 02/2019 **LG Electronics Inc.**, Seoul, Korea

Research Intern, CTO Division

06/2018 – 08/2018 **Wesleyquest Inc.**, Seoul, Korea

Research Associate

Honors and Awards

| 2022 | Gary Marsden Travel Award (Full travel support for UIST '22: \$2,800 USD), ACM SIGCHI |
|------|---|
| 2018 | Big Data Contest (3rd Place, Prize Money: \$900 USD), NIA and Korea Big Data Forum |
| 2018 | AI Novel Writing Competition (2 nd Place, Prize Money: \$18,000 USD), KT Corporation and |
| | KOCCA |
| 2017 | Academic Research Competition (2nd Place, Prize Money: \$180 USD), Hanyang University |

2014 – 2018 Merit-based Scholarship (6 semesters), *Hanyang University*

Academic Services

Paper ACM CHI ('22)

Reviewing IEEE PacificVis ('20, '21)

Student ACM UIST ('22)

Volunteering

^{*} denotes equal contributions.

Press Coverage

Nov2022The Road to Becoming a Published Researcher, IEEE Computer SocietyAug2018Writing Novels on Its Own... AI Contests Human Creativity, KBS (Korean)

3/3